Guide to the Charles and Shirley Weiss Collection of Opera Ephemera, 1951-2003 RL.11139
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charles and Shirley Weiss collection of opera ephemera
1951-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Weiss, Charles, 1918-
Weiss, Shirley, 1921-2010
RL.11139
4.5 Linear Feet 3 boxes
Collection contains programs from 1386 operas attended around the world from 1951-2003 by Drs. Charles and Shirley Weiss.
Arrangement
Programs are sorted alphabetically by opera title.
Biographical / Historical
Charles and Shirley Weiss were professors at the University of North Carolina, and were involved in a number of philanthropic efforts at UNC and Duke University. Charles M. Weiss (b. 1918) was a UNC professor of environmental biology from 1956 until his retirement in 1989. He and his wife Shirley were married for 68 years. Shirley Friedlander Weiss (1921-2010) was one of the first women faculty members at UNC Chapel Hill. She earned her Ph.D. in Economics from Duke University in 1973, and was a pioneer in urban research. She served as Associate Research Director of the Center for Urban and Regional Studies, and was also Acting Director of the Women's Center at UNC. The couple also founded the Weiss Urban Livability Fellowship Program at UNC Chapel Hill's Graduate School.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Charles and Shirley Weiss Collection of Opera Ephemera were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2016.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of 1386 opera programs collected from around the world by Charles and Shirley Weiss between 1951 and 2003. The programs are also detailed in a spreadsheet, documenting performance, date, location, performers, and other notable information about each program.
The spreadsheet is available at: https://duke.box.com/v/weissoperas-spreadsheet
The opera programs included represent a range of performances including classic, contemporary, and lesser-known operas. Venues are from around the world.
Opera -- 20th century; Opera -- United States -- North Carolina; Weiss, Charles, 1918-; Weiss, Shirley, 1921-2010
- Abelard Heloise (Page Auditorium, Durham, NC), 1982 February 23 (Box 1)
- Abu Hassan (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1989 January 29 (Box 1)
- Acis Galatea (Duke University, Durham, NC), 1975 November 9 (Box 1)
- Acis Galatea (Dock Street Theater, Charleston, SC), 1994 June 3 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  The Westminster Choir and the Spoleto Festival Orchestra also performed
- Admeto (Opera Australia, Sydney Opera House, Sydney, Australia), 1998 January 20 (Box 1)
- Adriana Lecouvreur (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1978 March 25 (Box 1)
- Adriana Lecouvreur (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1983 March 4 (Box 1)
- Adriana Lecouvreur (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1994 March 26 (Box 1)
- Agrippina (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1992 January 25 (Box 1)
- Agrippina (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 2002 April 11 (Box 1)
- Die Agyptische Helena (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1986 August 1 (Box 1)
- Die Agyptische Helena (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 2001 July 21 (Box 1)
- Aida (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1978 November 25 (Box 1)
- Aida (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1979 November 9 (Box 1)
- Aida (Raleigh Little Theatre, Raleigh, NC), 1983 June 19 (Box 1)
- Aida (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1983 October 7 (Box 1)
- Aida (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1984 June 27 (Box 1)
- Aida (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1985 January 3 (Box 1)
- Aida (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1989 January 21 (Box 1)
- Aida (Opera House, Washington, DC), 1990 March 4 (Box 1)
- Aida (Seattle Opera, Seattle, WA), 1992 August 22 (Box 1)
- Aida (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1994 January 29 (Box 1)
- Aida (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1995 January 22 (Box 1)
- Aida (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1995 October 27 (Box 1)
- Aida (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1997 February 20 (Box 1)
- Aida (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1997 March 6 (Box 1)
- Aida (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1998 November 6 (Box 1)
- Aida (Brown Theater, Wortham Theater Center, Houston, TX), 1999 October 30 (Box 1)
- Aida (Royal Albert Hall, London, England), 2001 February 24 (Box 1)
- Akhnaten (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1985 November 8 (Box 1)
- Albert Herring (San Diego Civic Theatre, San Diego, CA), 1991 February 17 (Box 1)
- Alcina (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1987 June 12 (Box 1)
  Libretto adapted anonymously from A. Fanzaglia's text of Riccardo Broschi's opera L'isola di Alcina
- Alcina (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1999 November 8 (Box 1)
- Alcina (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 2002 November 19 (Box 1)
- Amahl and the Night Visitors (City Theatre, Wellington, New Zealand), 1993 December 16 (Box 1)
  Program missing
- L'Amico Fritz (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1988 January 1 (Box 1)
- Amistad (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1997 December 8 (Box 1)
- L'Amore Dei Tre Re (NY State Theatre: Lincoln Center, New York, NY), 1982 April 9 (Box 1)
- L'Amour de Loin (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 2002 July 27 (Box 1)
- Andrea Chenier (Lyric Theater, Baltimore, MD), 1955 March 28 (Box 1)
- Andrea Chenier (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1979 November 23 (Box 1)
- Andrea Chenier (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1992 December 8 (Box 1)
- Andrea Chenier (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1995 December 12 (Box 1)
- Andrea Chenier (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1996 November 11 (Box 1)
- Anna Bolena (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1981 April 17 (Box 1)
- Anna Bolena (Opera House, Washington, DC), 1993 November 13 (Box 1)
- Anna Bolena (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1995 September 21 (Box 1)
- Antony and Cleopatra (Gaillard Municipal Auditorium, Charleston, SC), 1983 May 28 (Box 1)
  Spoleto Festival, USA
- Antony and Cleopatra (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1991 October 14 (Box 1)
  Libretto based on text by William Shakespeare
- Arabella (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1983 March 5 (Box 1)
- Arabella (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1983 August 6 (Box 1)
- Arabella (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1984 March 8 (Box 1)
- Arabella (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1994 November 11 (Box 1)
- Arabella (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1997 August 6 (Box 1)
- Arabella (Brown Theater, Wortham Theater Center, Houston, TX), 1998 April 19 (Box 1)
- Arabella (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1998 September 24 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1979 March 2 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1981 October 24 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1982 April 25 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Dock Street Theater, Charleston, SC), 1984 May 27 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1987 September 26 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1991 June 21 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1993 March 27 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Vienna State Opera, Vienna, Austria), 1993 April 7 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1994 February 8 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Opera Australia, Sydney Opera House, Sydney, Australia), 1997 January 7 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1997 October 10 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1998 November 21 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1999 July 28 (Box 1)
- Ariadne auf Naxos (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 2002 September 9 (Box 1)
- Arianna (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1998 June 19 (Box 1)
- Ariodante (Dock Street Theater, Charleston, SC), 1985 May 27 (Box 1)
- Ariodante (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1987 July 31 (Box 1)
- Ariodante (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1999 September 30 (Box 1)
- Arlecchinata (The Albert Simons Center for the Arts, Charleston, SC), 1984 June 3 (Box 1)
- Armida (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1995 June 20 (Box 1)
- Ashiya Otome (Seattle Center Opera House, Seattle, WA), 1989 September 2 (Box 1)
- Ashoka's Dream (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1997 July 26 (Box 1)
  World Premiere
- The Aspen Papers (Dallas Opera, Dallas, TX), 1988 November 19 (Box 1)
- The Aspen Papers (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1990 January 27 (Box 1)
- Attila (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1980 November 1 (Box 1)
  Libretto after the play "Attila, King of the Huns," by Zacharias Werner
- Attila (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1991 November 24 (Box 1)
- Attila (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1996 April 10 (Box 1)
- Attila (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 2000 December 2 (Box 1)
- Autumn Valentine (Witherspoon Concert Hall, Joslyn Art Museum, Omaha, NE), 1992 September 20 (Box 1)
- The Ballad of Baby Doe (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1997 February 1 (Box 1)
- The Ballad of Baby Doe (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 2001 April 12 (Box 1)
- The Ballad of Baby Doe (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 2001 September 23 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Stockholm Opera, Stockholm, Sweden), 1966 August 25 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Hill Music Hall, Chapel Hill, NC), 1975 January 31 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (National Opera Company, Durham, NC), 1977 January 28 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (John F. Kennedy Center, Washington, DC), 1977 May 11 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (National Opera Company, Durham, NC), 1978 July 9 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1982 March 25 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1982 June 16 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1985 June 23 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Page Auditorium, Durham, NC), 1987 September 30 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1988 October 29 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1989 December 27 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1992 February 15 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1994 July 9 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1994 October 31 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Eisenhower Theater, New York, NY), 1996 January 28 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1996 February 3 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1996 October 23 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (L.A. Opera, Los Angeles, CA), 1997 March 4 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1997 October 25 (Box 1)
- The Barber of Seville (Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 2001 January 25 (Box 1)
- The Bartered Bride (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1978 November 25 (Box 1)
- The Bartered Bride (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1992 October 19 (Box 1)
- The Bartered Bride (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1995 February 5 (Box 1)
- The Bartered Bride (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1996 October 10 (Box 1)
- Beatrice and Benedict (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1998 August 6 (Box 1)
- Beauty and the Beast (Houston Grand Opera, Houston, TX), 1992 February 20 (Box 1)
- Beauty and the Beast (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1987 June 13 (Box 1)
- The Beggar's Opera (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1992 August 12 (Box 1)
- La Belle Helene (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1995 June 24 (Box 1)
- Betrothal in a Dream (Eisenhower Theater, Washington, DC), 1996 January 30 (Box 1)
- Betrothal in a Monastery (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1998 May 9 (Box 1)
- Billy Budd (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1979 March 24 (Box 1)
- Billy Budd (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1985 November 22 (Box 1)
- Billy Budd (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1992 April 11 (Box 1)
- Billy Budd (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1993 June 18 (Box 1)
- Billy Budd (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1997 March 8 (Box 1)
- Billy Budd (Houston Grand Opera, Houston, TX), 1998 February 14 (Box 1)
- The Birthday of the Infanta (Gaillard Municipal Auditorium, Charleston, SC), 1993 May 29 (Box 1)
- Black River (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1994 June 24 (Box 1)
- Black Water (Plays Players Theatre, Philadelphia, PA), 1997 April 26 (Box 1)
- Blond Eckbert (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1994 July 30 (Box 1)
- Blond Eckbert (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1994 August 3 (Box 1)
- Bluebeard's Castle (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1989 February 4 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Goldovsky Opera Theater, Durham, NC), 1978 March 13 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (The Royal Opera, London, England), 1980 June 10 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1981 December 18 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (English National Opera, London, England), 1982 December 30 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1983 March 5 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Opera Colorado, Denver, CO), 1983 April 8 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1984 November 3 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1987 January 10 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Des Moines Metro Opera, Indianola, Iowa), 1987 July 12 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1988 June 11 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1989 March 11 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1990 November 16 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1991 June 20 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Opera Australia, Sydney Opera House, Sydney, Australia), 1993 January 15 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1993 January 23 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1993 August 7 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1993 September 22 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1993 November 20 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1995 March 11 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1996 April 13 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1996 November 19 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1997 December 9 (Box 1)
- La Boheme (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 2001 June 23 (Box 1)
- Boris Godunov (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1978 February 25 (Box 1)
- Boris Godunov (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1982 September 24 (Box 1)
- Boris Godunov (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1983 November 26 (Box 1)
- Boris Godunov (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1990 November 10 (Box 1)
- Boris Godunov (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1992 September 16 (Box 1)
- Boris Godunov (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1994 October 10 (Box 1)
- Boris Godunov (Houston Grand Opera, Houston, TX), 1997 May 4 (Box 1)
- Boris Godunov (Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1999 February 28 (Box 1)
- Buoso's Ghost (The Orpheum Theatre, Memphis, TN), 1997 January 25 (Box 1)
- Die Burgschaft (Sottile Theatre, Charleston, SC), 1999 June 4 (Box 1)
- Die Burgschaft (Sottile Theatre, Charleston, SC), 1999 June 12 (Box 1)
- La Calisto (Glimmerglass Opera, Cooperstown, NY), 1996 August 25 (Box 1)
- Il Campanello di Notte (Festival International d'Art Lyrique, Aix-en-Provence, France), 1977 July 21 (Box 1)
- Candide (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1982 October 29 (Box 1)
- Candide (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1994 June 23 (Box 1)
- Candide (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1994 December 6 (Box 1)
- Capriccio (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1993 June 28 (Box 1)
- Capriccio (The Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1993 July 24 (Box 1)
- Capriccio (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1994 December 5 (Box 1)
- I Capuleti e I Montecchi (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1985 November 30 (Box 1)
- I Capuleti e I Montecchi (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1991 November 25 (Box 1)
- I Capuleti e I Montecchi (Opera National de Paris, Paris, France), 1998 November 26 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Teatro Colon, Buenos Aires, Argentina), 1968 July 24 (Box 1)
- Carmen (John F. Kennedy Center, New York, NY), 1977 May 11 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Carolina Theatre, Durham, NC), 1978 July 16 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1978 December 9 (Box 1)
- Carmen (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1981 October 18 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Vivian Beaumont Theater, Lincoln Center, New York, NY), 1984 March 10 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Sack Cinema 9, Copley Place, Boston, MA), 1984 October 17 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1986 March 14 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1987 June 14 (Box 1)
- Carmen (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1995 March 27 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Triangle Opera Theater, Durham, NC), 1995 May 31 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Triangle Opera Theater, Durham, NC), 1995 June 2 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Triangle Opera Theater, Durham, NC), 1995 June 4 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Triangle Opera Theater, Durham, NC), 1995 June 6 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1995 October 28 (Box 1)
- Carmen (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1996 October 22 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1996 October 31 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1997 October 25 (Box 1)
- Carmen (San Francisco Opera Center, Chapel Hill, NC), 1997 November 13 (Box 1)
- Carmen (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1998 June 27 (Box 1)
- Carmen (The Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1999 July 10 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 2000 March 3 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Houston Grand Opera, Houston, TX), 2000 October 28 (Box 1)
- Carmen (Spoleto Festival, Charleston, SC), 2002 May 28 (Box 1)
- Carmina Burana (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1997 April 4 (Box 1)
- Carmina Burana (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1998 September 19 (Box 1)
- Casanova (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1985 November 1 (Box 1)
- Cavalleria Rusticana (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1978 January 28 (Box 1)
- Cavalleria Rusticana (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1979 November 10 (Box 1)
- Cavalleria Rusticana (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1987 November 1 (Box 1)
- Cavalleria Rusticana (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1992 March 7 (Box 1)
- Cavalleria Rusticana (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1994 November 12 (Box 1)
- Cendrillon (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1982 November 13 (Box 1)
- Cendrillon (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1988 February 27 (Box 1)
- Cendrillon (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1993 June 19 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (The National Opera Company, Raleigh, NC), 1976 March 11 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1982 October 16 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (Page Auditorium, Durham, NC), 1984 October 25 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (Des Moines Metro Opera, Des Moines, IA), 1985 July 5 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1987 June 13 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1993 January 28 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1995 October 18 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1997 October 24 (Box 1)
- La Cenerentola (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 2002 September 28 (Box 1)
- Central Park: Strawberry Fields (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1999 November 16 (Box 1)
- Central Park: The Festival of Regrets (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1999 November 16 (Box 1)
- Central Park: The Food of Love (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1999 November 16 (Box 1)
- Chip and his Dog (Spoleto Festival, Charleston, SC), 1980 May 29 (Box 1)
- Christophe Colomb (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1992 December 11 (Box 1)
- Le Cid (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1981 October 17 (Box 1)
- Le Cid (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1993 January 31 (Box 1)
- Le Cid (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1999 November 13 (Box 1)
- Claudia Legare (Duke University, Durham, NC), 1981 July 24 (Box 1)
- La Clemenza di Tito (Grand Theatre de Geneve, Geneva, Switzerland), 1980 June 7 (Box 1)
- La Clemenza di Tito (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1984 November 2 (Box 1)
- La Clemenza di Tito (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1993 November 28 (Box 1)
- La Clemenza di Tito (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1996 June 21 (Box 1)
- La Clemenza di Tito (Opera Australia, Sydney Opera House, Sydney, Australia), 1997 January 4 (Box 1)
- La Clemenza di Tito (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 2000 April 12 (Box 1)
- La Clemenza di Tito (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 2002 July 13 (Box 1)
- Cold Sassy Tree (Houston Grand Opera, Houston, TX), 2000 April 28 (Box 1)
- Comedy on the Bridge (Des Moines Metro Opera, Des Moines, IA), 1986 July 12 (Box 1)
- Le Comte Ory (Spoleto Festival, Charleston, SC), 1993 June 5 (Box 1)
- The Confidence Man (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1982 August 13 (Box 1)
- The Conquistador (San Diego Opera, San Diego, CA), 1997 March 1 (Box 1)
- The Consul (Spoleto Festival, Charleston, SC), 1977 May 30 (Box 1)
- The Consul (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1996 November 16 (Box 1)
- The Consul (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 2001 January 26 (Box 1)
- Le Coq D'Or (New York City Opera, New York, NY), 1979 April 15 (Box 1)
- The Coronation of Poppea (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1981 July 12 (Box 1)
- The Coronation of Poppea (The Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1986 August 7 (Box 1)
- The Coronation of Poppea (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1987 February 6 (Box 1)
- The Coronation of Poppea (Spoleto Festival, Charleston, SC), 1991 June 4 (Box 1)
- The Coronation of Poppea (Welsh National Opera, London, England), 1998 March 3 (Box 1)
- The Coronation of Poppea (San Francisco Opera, San Francisco, CA), 1998 June 28 (Box 1)
- The Coronation of Poppea (Houston Grand Opera, Houston, TX), 2001 March 8 (Box 1)
- Il Corsaro (San Diego Opera, San Diego, CA), 1982 June 20 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Festival International d'Art Lyrique, Aix-en-Provence, France), 1977 July 26 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (UNC-CH Opera Theater Workshop, Chapel Hill, NC), 1979 March 30 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1982 January 29 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Page Auditorium, Durham, NC), 1986 September 24 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Page Auditorium, Durham, NC), 1986 September 26 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1988 March 26 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1989 November 10 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1990 February 3 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Lyric Opera of Chicago, Chicago, IL), 1993 November 22 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1996 March 2 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Los Angeles Music Center Opera, Los Angeles, CA), 1996 March 4 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (The Washington Opera, Washington, DC), 1996 March 12 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Metropolitan Opera, New York, NY), 1996 December 6 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Opera Theatre of St. Louis, St. Louis, MO), 1997 June 18 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1997 July 2 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Opera Australia, Sydney Opera House, Sydney, Australia), 1998 January 3 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Houston Grand Opera, Houston, TX), 2001 February 10 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Memorial Hall, Chapel Hill, NC), 2001 November 5 (Box 1)
- Cosi Fan Tutte (Spoleto Festival, Charleston, SC), 2002 June 4 (Box 1)
- Countess Maritza (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1995 July 5 (Box 1)
- Countess Maritza (Santa Fe Opera, Santa Fe, NM), 1999 August 14 (Box 1)